TOP SECRET!
We can go right away.
What are you doing?
I don't need a film.
Give me the original.
We need it to get Katelbach
and Heymann out of prison.
What's two political inmates
against millions of war victims?
I photographed it for you.
Headquarters suspects
that all photographs are fakes.
You know that.
Same goes for the courts here.
Please give it to me.
No.
I don't want to hurt you.
So…
I'm sorry.
No. Not in there!
Leave me alone!
HOUSE SONNENBORN
BLOCK 3
Get out. In there. Be quiet.
No!
Stay still now!
Don't make such a fuss.
- Shut up!
- Quiet!
No!
Dr. Schwarz?
You?
What are you doing here?
- What's going on?
- Open the door.
- Let me out.
- How am I supposed to do that?
What happened to Rudi?
I… I didn't want that.
- Malzig was a good man.
- What are you talking about?
Talk to me!
- Talk to me! You falsified documents.
- No.
You did! And Rudi knew about it.
- Why? Why did you do that?
- Because they threatened me.
What do they have on you?
An error.
Malpractice.
I was asked to write a report
for the court.
For Judge Voss.
And I made a mistake…
and that's how it started.
Voss…
He's the worst of all.
A monster.
Now he's holding court up there…
and plays God.
Who are these people?
What are you doing? No! No!
What are you doing with me now?
Please…
No!
- Let me go!
- Shut your face!
SERVING THE TRUE LAW
OF THE GERMANS
TO THE YARD
Now or never.
Tell me if you see a crank.
You can drive?
I'll keep watch.
Defendant, you have indecently
assaulted a German woman.
You have manhandled
and abused her to death.
This is correct, yes?
Yes?
I was finally convicted. Yes.
You call that justice.
Seven ridiculous years in prison.
And on top of that,
you were released after four years.
For good conduct.
- This is a charade.
- I beg you, Your Honor.
- Have mercy.
- Mercy…
Mercy?
Now he's standing here
whimpering for mercy.
So we'll have mercy…
with this brutish subject.
In the name of the White Hand
I will now issue the revised judgement.
The defendant Heinrich Schüttler,
for rape and malevolent intention
is sentenced to death.
The sentence is to be enforced
immediately.
In the name of the German people.
- Justice follows on injustice.
- Order follows on barbarism.
Strength follows on weakness.
Executioner, discharge your duty.
I was finally sentenced.
I served my sentence!
Please. Please!
I beg for mercy! Please!
Here, I've got one.
So far I know it.
Right. And now…
There!
- Operator, which number?
- Connect me to Rath, Weissensee 4905.
- Please repeat.
- Weissensee 4905.
Answer. Answer the phone!
Stop. Freeze!
Open up!
Open this door right now!
I am warning you. The police is
in the house, and I'll call them
if you don't open this door
right this instance.
What are you doing here?
I'm asking you that.
Toni babe.
We wanted to scarper.
What?
With an automobile.
Renate can drive.
We're just waiting for the driver
to get lost.
Now. Quick!
Wait.
You two call Detective Sergeant Rath.
Weissensee 49-05.
Memorize it. 49-05. OK?
Call him and tell him I'm here.
He knows.
Off you go.
I'll stay with her.
Sure?
Fine.
Come on then.
Freeze! Freeze!
Now I've got you, bitch.
I'll kill you.
I'll slice you up.
The guns. The guns!
Come!
- Operator, which number?
- Weissensee 49-05.
- Hello?
- Mr. Rath?
Who is this?
Schwarz, Joseph.
Doctor of medicine.
You are accused
of having betrayed the White Hand.
You schemed against our goals
by word and deed
and therefore threatened
the entire operation.
And now you stand here before us
and pretend you haven't got a clue
about anything.
Come, let me show you your lookout.
Get down!
Here, but stay down.
Follow me!
…don't have the nerves.
A German organization like ours…
You are a classic example
of the spinelessness
which we so often talk about…
and for which from our point of view
there is no sympathy, no…
Nobody move!
Get away from the door!
Away from the door!
Sit down!
I have two of these.
Two times eight bullets.
I'll get 16 of you.
We will wait here now.
All of us.
I want absolute quiet in the room
until the police are here.
And they're on their way.
- Miss, this is deprivation of liberty…
- Shut up or I'll shoot!
- But…
- Shut your face! Shut up!
Quiet!
- Sit down.
- Get away from the door!
Get away!
Open up!
Get away from the door!
Make room. Make room!
Police. Hands up!
Arrest them all!
Take them away!
Every single one of them!
Come in.
Mrs. Behnke, come on in.
I'm afraid they struck hard.
Who?
I don't know.
But I can't really complain
about a lack of enemies.
Where's Miss Seegers?
Except for this,
there is no trace of her.
She didn't turn up for work
and didn't excuse herself.
My calls are unanswered,
and our friends don't know where she is.
In three and a half years of working
with her, this has never happened.
Have you called the police?
Should be difficult
before we talk to the comrade.
- Because there is nothing missing.
- But she is missing.
Yes. And with her the only thing
which has come into the possession
of our office illegally.
- Gregorius' papers.
- Yes.
And I can't report it
without getting prosecuted myself.
- I have searched everywhere.
- But the deadline is in a few hours.
First thing I did was apply for an
extension in order to gather evidence.
And?
The court is obliged
to examine my application.
We'll know more tomorrow afternoon
at the latest.
- But it's going to be difficult.
- Why?
Apart from the obvious partisanship
of the judge,
such things are only very rarely granted.
We need to file a missing person report.
Right away.
The only question is
if Miss Seegers really is missing or…
gone into hiding.
Taking the documents with her.
No way.
Comrade Kulanin should have taken the
one-o'clock train before you, correct?
Yes.
When is the last train?
He won't come.
He will, he keeps his word.
He won't come and
he didn't procure a gun, either.
I think something must have happened
and the comrade
has no room to maneuver.
Lieutenant Kulani is your and my superior
and therefore not accountable to us.
What if he has betrayed us?
I won't doubt the directives from Moscow.
Please don't misunderstand me.
But I've known Oskar for a long time
and I've never seen him like yesterday.
Let's focus on the operation.
If he doesn't show,
are there guns in the cabinet?
Fine. So we have everything we need.
If the gun is from this cabin,
the investigators will put one
and one together.
The fascist pig must be executed.
With or without order.
So, open the cabinet.
Now.
There is no turning back, comrade.
I'm counting on you.
Right.
You have one attempt, one single one.
Or all this will collapse again.
You need to be quick.
Quick as a greyhound.
Well done, Helga.
Well done by both of us.
Let the ladder down.
What is it?
Helga! Let the ladder down!
Right now!
Helga!
Helga, let the ladder down!
Open the hatch!
Helga!
Come back!
MOKA EFTI PRESENTS
CLOSED
- What is this?
- You can't get in, you're banned.
Sorry, the boss said so.
Out of the way, you squirt.
What are you doing here?
Gentlemen.
What am I doing here?
Closing the joint.
What? You're doing no such thing.
I'll tidy up in there, don't worry.
Forget it. The joint is history.
For you, too.
What are you talking about?
Who were they?
The new owners.
- What?
- The joint is sold.
You can't, it's mine.
Esther, you haven't paid
your installments in eight months.
And as a creditor,
I've exerted my right to foreclose.
That's all.
You dare taking the joint away from me?
After everything I've done for you?
Can you please walk the lady to her car?
Take your paws off me.
BRAWL AT MOKA EFTI
BETWEEN SU AND SS
After this roughhouse we must
disempower the SA. Immediately.
Stennes and his confidantes
are a threat to public safety.
He has got the SA behind him again.
We need to set an example.
Do we? I've always had the impression
you rather enjoy chaos in the streets.
This is your chance to get rid
of the SA once and for all.
Why won't you seize it?
Because I'm not the executioner
of your plans.
You can settle your private feud with this
guy Stennes amongst yourselves,
but not on the back of the Berlin police.
You're going deerstalking
on the weekend. Good hunting!
Councillor.
Here is good.
You will bring him here tomorrow.
Understood?
I have to get back.
Wendt will be here soon.
I'll find out about Kulani.
He can't disappear
without us knowing where he is.
Helga.
- Where is she?
- She's gone.
She left me down here, the bitch.
Don't go. Please!
You were fooled by a lie. Mr. Goldstein!
Your father's diamond
never reached Berlin.
How do you know this name?
The Blue Rothschild, or that which
you take for it, I have had forged.
The original was lost.
Odessa, MS Silésia.
You want the truth
about your father's death.
And the truth about the Blue Rothschild.
Who says this isn't a trap?
That the other one won't come back?
- Why should I believe you?
- Because the ladder was still up there.
She abandoned me down here,
the floozy. I'm telling the truth.
And the truth about the night…
of the 18th of March, 1915.
What do you know about it?
I'll tell you, and you let me go.
OK.
But I'm warning you. If you lie to me,
you won't get out of here alive.
I won't lie to you.
Your father
had entrusted my husband
with the stone.
He was supposed to take it to Berlin
in his diplomat's luggage.
To your Jewish church.
That evening, we had had dinner on land,
in the Hotel Europa.
My husband was very jolly.
Get to the point.
I stopped at the promenade,
probably with lots of members
of your family, too.
Keep going.
And after about 15 minutes…
there was a huge explosion.
And then the attack of the British.
The torpedo was a straight hit.
Mrs. Nyssen.
I read up on this.
There was no attack
by the British that day.
There wasn't a single act of war
in the Odessa harbor that day.
But I… I was there.
I saw it with my own eyes.
No.
You are lying.
I…
This is from my father.
Parasite!
Bloodsucker!
The eternal Jew!
I'll see you in hell.
Helga!
Helga.
You're back.
That's all you can think of?
While I nearly croaked?
Helga…
Please forgive me.
There was no way, I tried everything.
Where have you been?
We were trapped on a barge.
I escaped.
What?
And Mother?
She's still there.
What?
Where is this barge?
I don't know.
Helga, where is this barge?
I don't know
if I'd find the way back there.
There was a forest.
And fields.
And… I walked for hours.
- We need to go there at once.
- Through the rain.
Helga.
Helga!
When you left…
we took the statements.
And they all…
The janitor, the staff, the youths,
they all spoke of a yard of the dead.
Or a wall of the dead.
An abandoned building.
Right behind the home.
So we started looking.
According to first estimates, there are
more than 150 dead people there.
Who are these men
who would do such a thing?
There are arrests being made
all over the Reich.
The organization around Voss
is called White Hand.
Most of them are state officials.
Judges, public prosecutors.
- Police officers, too.
- The White Hand…
- What do they want?
- A new law?
I don't know.
Discipline, order.
Our system is too lax for them.
So they took it into their own hands.
For the children,
the home was their last chance.
If they escaped anyway,
they would have forfeited their lives.
And they're not ashamed of themselves?
The way they were sitting there…
And they were so sure of themselves.
They are murderers.
And they will be brought to trial.
Thanks to you and your commitment.
Gereon.
I shot at them.
I have never shot at anyone.
- You didn't kill anyone.
- Yes, I did.
Kuschke.
They say one of them
is still in critical condition.
His name is Brinkmann.
He has a wife and three children.
He attacked you.
If you hadn't shot him,
you'd be dead now.
And that gang would be running free.
It's open.
- Good evening.
- Evening.
Don't we want
to do everything differently?
Everything differently.
Everything differently?
We could leave.
- Could we?
- Away from here.
Politics, all of it.
Here and now, in this moment…
there is nothing between us.
No politics, no age, no general, nothing.
There is only us.
The two of us.
I want to go away with you.
I forgot the "I"
And only know "we"
With the lover I became two
And above all being grew the "we".